<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" 
xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" 
xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0 /home/lopez/grobid/grobid-home/schemas/xsd/Grobid.xsd"
 xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
	<teiHeader xml:lang="en">
		<encodingDesc>
			<appInfo>
				<application version="0.5.5-SNAPSHOT" ident="GROBID" when="2019-03-20T09:09+0000">
					<ref target="https://github.com/kermitt2/grobid">GROBID - A machine learning software for extracting information from scholarly documents</ref>
				</application>
			</appInfo>
		</encodingDesc>
		<fileDesc>
			<titleStmt>
				<title level="a" type="main">Learning Program Structure and Assigning Style Grade by k-means clustering and Softmax Regression</title>
			</titleStmt>
			<publicationStmt>
				<publisher/>
				<availability status="unknown"><licence/></availability>
			</publicationStmt>
			<sourceDesc>
				<biblStruct>
					<analytic>
						<author>
							<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Homero</forename><surname>Roman</surname></persName>
							<affiliation key="aff0">
								<orgName type="department">Final Project</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution">Stanford University</orgName>
								<address>
									<postCode>CS229 2016</postCode>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<author>
							<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Roman</forename></persName>
							<affiliation key="aff0">
								<orgName type="department">Final Project</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution">Stanford University</orgName>
								<address>
									<postCode>CS229 2016</postCode>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<title level="a" type="main">Learning Program Structure and Assigning Style Grade by k-means clustering and Softmax Regression</title>
					</analytic>
					<monogr>
						<imprint>
							<date/>
						</imprint>
					</monogr>
				</biblStruct>
			</sourceDesc>
		</fileDesc>
		<profileDesc>
			<abstract>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Abstract:</head><p>The goal of this research is to figure out how to automatically assign a style grade to a program and provide style feedback. More specifically, the procedure employs Karel Programs from the first assignment of the CS106A class.</p><p>Motivation:</p></div>
			</abstract>
		</profileDesc>
	</teiHeader>
	<text xml:lang="en">
		<body>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Motivation:</head><p>While identifying a functionality mistake can be straightforward, identifying style mistakes is subject to subtle conventions and an infinite number of possible programs. This poses a problem for students trying to get feedback on their program style while they are still working on the assignment.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Approach:</head><p> Cluster the training data of working programs into k means  Explore three clustering strategies and choose one  Create a Logistic Regression or Naive Bayes model of the functions of the programs in each cluster including non-working programs and decide for each function of a test program whether the function is well decomposed and whether is well formatted. Use this to provide feedback to the student.  Then average these two parameters for all functions in a program and use them to describe the program. </p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Clustering results:</head><p> Clustering by counts of primitives is very susceptible to unnecessary command calls. Also it does not distinguish between call times.  Clustering by pouring all coordinates may be susceptible to outlying programs that tend to spend too much time at a certain place.  Double k-means overall seems to address the issues above and can even be implemented for variable times. However, it breaks down with infinite loops.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Softmax results:</head><p> Softmax with clustering performed with 87% accuracy while Softmax without clustering performed at about 75%. Therefore, clustering before hand seems to perform better.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Future Work:</head><p> Apply these results into a purely Java setting  Account for variable naming and comment content.</p></div><figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" type="table" xml:id="tab_0" validated="false"><head></head><label></label><figDesc> Finally add whether the program works to the program vector and use this vectors to run Softmax Regression on the test program and decide its style grade. Implementation: . [#move(); #putBeeper(); #pickBeeper(); #turnLeft();#turnRight();#turnAround()] Strategy 1 Parse into primitives And create a vector with counts of each primitive Keep track of Karel's Coordinates over time Strategy 2 Cluster into k-means [time,x,y; time2,x2,y2; …] Run preliminary k- means to find cluster of a single programStrategy 3Logistic Regression or Naïve Bayes to decide whether a program's function is well decomposed and well formatted.</figDesc><table>Implementation: 

. 

[#move(); #putBeeper(); #pickBeeper(); 
#turnLeft();#turnRight();#turnAround()] 

Strategy 1 

Parse into primitives 
And create a vector with 
counts of each primitive 

Keep track of Karel's 
Coordinates over time 

Strategy 2 

Cluster into k-means 

[time,x,y; 
time2,x2,y2; …] 

Run 
preliminary k-
means to find 
cluster of a 
single program 

Strategy 3 

Fit the functions in the programs in each cluster 
using collected properties of each function 

[between 2-10 lines?; 
Appropriate line length; 
No repeating code; 
label] 

[Right indentation; 
No blank lines; 
Commented] 

Is the function well 
decomposed? 

Is the function well formatted? 

Then, take average over a program. 
[Program decomposed; program well formatted; Program Works] 

Fit Softmax Model 

Report Style grades for the 
program overall and each 
function. Provide feedback 
on how to improve the 
style of each function. 

100 programs from 
the same assignment 

</table></figure>
		</body>
		<back>
			<div type="references">

				<listBibl/>
			</div>
		</back>
	</text>
</TEI>
