<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" 
xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" 
xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0 /home/lopez/grobid/grobid-home/schemas/xsd/Grobid.xsd"
 xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
	<teiHeader xml:lang="en">
		<encodingDesc>
			<appInfo>
				<application version="0.5.5-SNAPSHOT" ident="GROBID" when="2019-03-20T09:17+0000">
					<ref target="https://github.com/kermitt2/grobid">GROBID - A machine learning software for extracting information from scholarly documents</ref>
				</application>
			</appInfo>
		</encodingDesc>
		<fileDesc>
			<titleStmt>
				<title level="a" type="main"></title>
			</titleStmt>
			<publicationStmt>
				<publisher/>
				<availability status="unknown"><licence/></availability>
			</publicationStmt>
			<sourceDesc>
				<biblStruct>
					<analytic>
					</analytic>
					<monogr>
						<imprint>
							<date/>
						</imprint>
					</monogr>
					<idno type="DOI">10.1001/archinte.166.10.1092</idno>
				</biblStruct>
			</sourceDesc>
		</fileDesc>
		<profileDesc>
			<abstract>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Discussion</head><p>In this work, we explored a head movement, a noisy signal in the medical domain which we confirm to be useful for predicting patient anxiety disorder. We faced an inherently small-data problem, since controlled participation in a VR experience is costly to collect. As such, we focused on featurization and model comparison to determine what features and methods are promising for evaluating anxiety through head movement. We conclude that the discrete Fourier Transform tends to be more predictive than summary statistics about the head movement data, as two of our three models perform better on DFT parameters, and our best model, a multinomial Naive Bayes on DFT features, considerably outperforms all baselines. Qualitatively, we see in the graph below why head movement data can be predictive of anxiety. We report largely negative results in our attempts to use random search on model weights to choose a high-quality mixture of experts, though our F1-optimized model does achieve the best combination of F1 and recall. Our CNN model underperformed classical baselines, likely due to a lack of data, though this was true even for very small CNNs, as shown by our hyperparameter search.</p></div>
			</abstract>
		</profileDesc>
	</teiHeader>
	<text xml:lang="en">
		<body>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><p>The train/dev data has 118 samples, and the test data had 30.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Anxiety Disorder Prediction from Virtual Reality Head Movements</head><p>Sarah Ciresi, John Hewitt, Cooper Raterink Overview This project uses VR-based head movement data to predict presence of an anxiety disorder. Researchers have established a relationship between type of head movements and mental illness <ref type="bibr" target="#b0">[1]</ref>. We use votes from an ensemble of machine learners to predict anxiety in patients based on hand-selected expert features, and compare the results to the predictions of a deep convolutional network.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Future Work</head><p>For further research, we are interested in "more expert" featurizations on the data, as well as extending the analysis to include the video data. We believe there likely exists a featurization related to movement patterns that would perform well, we just struggled to find it. Also, in an ideal world, we'd like to collect more data so that a deep model would be more effective. We could also incorporate what happens during the virtual reality experience into the analysis. Our chief goal in future work would be increased precision.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Results</head></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Methods</head><p>As we experimented more and more with classifiers, we realized our results were extremely noisy, and were suffering from high variance. So, we decided to aggregate the outputs of the models we had been using into a ensemble voting system. Instead of naively using uniform weights we do a random search [4] on the voter weights as well as the decision threshold. We conducted this search and all hyperparameter choices using hold-one-out validation on data with disjoint participants from our test participants.</p><p>We compared this random search-learned classifier model with a Convolutional Neural Network with five layers: a convolutional layer, an average pooling layer, a ReLU activation layer, and two dense layers. We also used dropout for regularization. The number of output filters, kernel size, and dropout rate were tuned to find the set of hyperparameters that yielded the highest precision, recall, and F1 scores. </p></div><figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" type="table" xml:id="tab_0" validated="false"><head>[ 2 ]</head><label>2</label><figDesc>Benjamin J Li et al. "A Public Database of Immersive VR Videos with Corresponding Ratings of Arousal, Valence, and Correlations between Head Movements and Self Report Measures". In: Frontiers in psychology 8 (2017), p. 2116. [3] Spitzer RL, Kroenke K, Williams JBW, Löwe B. A Brief Measure for Assessing Generalized Anxiety DisorderThe GAD-7. Arch Intern Med. 2006;166(10):1092-1097. doi:10.1001/archinte.166.10.1092 [4] Bergstra, James, and Yoshua Bengio. "Random search for hyper-parameter optimization." Journal of Machine Learning Research13.Feb (2012): 281-305. Data Andrea Goldstein, from Stanford's Williams PANLab, advised us on this project and provided VR head movement data gathered during the ENGAGE study. Participants' head movements were tracked while experiencing virtual reality environments including positive experiences, negative experiences, and calm experiences. For each participant, we have a binary label as to whether they are judged as having high anxiety according to a quantitative metric called GAD7 [3].</figDesc><table>Ratings 
of 
Arousal, 
Valence, 
and 
Correlations between Head Movements and 
Self Report Measures". In: Frontiers in 
psychology 8 (2017), p. 2116. 

[3] Data 

</table></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" type="table" xml:id="tab_1" validated="false"><head></head><label></label><figDesc>CNN Hyperparameter Search, Development SetAffine Random Search-Learned Classical Classifier Ensemble</figDesc><table>Predictor 
F1 
Precision Recall 

LogReg -summary 

23.5 
18.2 
33.3 

D Tree -summary 

35.3 
25.6 
57.3 

N Bayes -summary 

37.0 
23.8 
83.3 

LogReg -DFT 

33.3 
25.0 
50.0 

D Tree -DFT 

26.2 
19.5 
40.3 

N Bayes -DFT 

43.5 
29.4 
83.3 

Uniform Weight 
Voter Ensemble 

35.7 
27.8 
50.0 

F1 Ensemble 

42.3 
27.8 
89.0 

Precision Ensemble 

9.3 
12.4 
7.7 

Recall Ensemble 

36.3 
22.8 
90.3 

CNN 

25.0 
16.6 
50.0 

Predict all 1s Baseline 

33.3 
20.0 100.0 

Predict 50/50 Baseline 

26.9 
18.8 
48.0 

Anxiety Prediction Model Comparison 

Filter Count 
Kernel Size 
Dropout 
Rate 

F-score 
Precision Recall 

16 
5 
0.5 
22.7 
17.9 
31.3 

10 
5 
0.3 
23.8 
17.9 
35.7 

32 
10 
0.5 
21.4 
42.9 
28.7 

16 
10 
0.3 
38.3 
32.1 
47.4 

32 
20 
0.3 
16.0 
11.0 
30.1 

Affine 

ReLU 

Affine+ 
Softmax 

Pool 

Conv 

Head Position 

ReLU 

1D Head Movement CNN </table></figure>
		</body>
		<back>

			<div type="acknowledgement">
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Features</head><p>We compute two separate featurizations on both the time-series data and the one-step differences: (1) a 30-point discrete Fourier Transform, and (2) summary statistics (mean, sum, variance)</p></div>
			</div>

			<div type="references">

				<listBibl>

<biblStruct xml:id="b0">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Head pose and movement analysis as an indicator of depres-sion</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Sharifa</forename><surname>Alghowinem</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Affective Computing and Intelligent Interaction (ACII), 2013 Humaine Associa-tion Conference on</title>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2013" />
			<biblScope unit="page" from="283" to="288" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

				</listBibl>
			</div>
		</back>
	</text>
</TEI>
